Guide to the Sears Family Papers SC0523
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sears family papers
1903-1985
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson)
Sears family.
SC0523
25 Linear Feet
These papers include correspondence, publications, photographs, business papers, genealogical materials, and ephemera of the Sears and Snedden families. Individuals represented in the collection include Jesse B. Sears, Stella Sears, Robert Sears, Pauline Sears, David Snedden, Genevra Snedden, Hope Snedden, and Janet Snedden. The correspondence primarily pertains to personal and family matters, with some mention of professional concerns. Also included are Robert Sears' school papers, from Palo Alto Union High School and from his undergraduate years at Stanford University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of the estate of Pauline Sears, 1993.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Jesse B. Sears was professor of education at Stanford University from 1912-1942. His son Robert Sears, psychologist, taught at the University of Iowa and at Harvard before joining the Stanford faculty in 1953. Pauline Snedden Sears (Mrs. Robert Sears) taught at Yale and Harvard; at Stanford she was a research associate with the Stanford Center in Research and Development in Teaching and administrator of the Elementary Teaching Training Program. David Snedden, Stanford class of 1897, was professor of education at Teacher's College of Columbia University from 1900 to 1935.
Description of the Collection
These papers include correspondence, publications, photographs, business papers, genealogical materials, and ephemera of the Sears and Snedden families. Individuals represented in the collection include Jesse B. Sears, Stella Sears, Robert Sears, Pauline Sears, David Snedden, Genevra Snedden, Hope Snedden, and Janet Snedden. The correspondence primarily pertains to personal and family matters, with some mention of professional concerns. Also included are Robert Sears' school papers, from Palo Alto Union High School and from his undergraduate years at Stanford University.
Educators -- Family relationships.; Psychologists -- Family relationships.; Families; Sears, Pauline Snedden.; Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson); Snedden, Janet Hildegarde.; Snedden family.; Sears family.; Snedden, Genevra Sisson; Sears, Jesse Brundage; Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson); Snedden, Hope.; Sears family.; Sears, Stella Richardson.; Snedden, David Samuel
- Jesse Sears: Family, Series 1
  - J.B. Sears: incoming correspondence, 1920’s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - J.B. Sears: incoming correspondence, 1930’s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - J.B. Sears: incoming and outgoing corr., 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Wallace Sterling to J.B. Sears, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: ca. 1920-1973 (with ND) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sears Family correspondence: 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sears Family correspondence: incoming from Clara Sears McCullough,1964-1972 (later Clara Sara Reed) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sears Family correspondence: ND (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sears Family correspondence: Photographs, 1964, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sears Family correspondence: J.R. Sears to J.B., 1972 (includes photographs) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Journal: “Trip to San Jacinto” (possibly Stella Sears) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Christmas cards; sympathy cards (Box 2)
  - J.B. Sears: Journals/Notebooks (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “The First Twenty Years of the Fellowship Forum, 1950-1970” (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “The Fellowship Forum: It’s First Twenty Years, 1950-1970” (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “Proposed Plans for Evaluating Facilities...” (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “Proposal for a Study of Major Issues in Teacher Education” (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “Family Autobiographies...” (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “Jimmy Butler’s Story of Himself and the Owl” (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “Proposal for a Comprehensive Study of Teacher Education,” draft (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - J.B. Sears Papers: “Proposal for a Comprehensive Study of Teacher Education,” final copy (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - J.B. Sears: Itenerary for European Trip (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - J.B. Sears: Correspondence: salary schedules (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - J.B. Sears: ephemera: death and birth records of Stella Louise Richardson (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - J.B. Sears: Sears genealogy (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - J.B. Sears: Sears genealogy (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - J.B. Sears: Sears genealogy (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - J.B. Sears: Sears genealogy (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - J.B. Sears: Sears genealogy (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Sears Genealogy, 1803-1961 (2 copies) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified corr. re. Sears family history, 1903-1914 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Robert Sears: School Ephemera, Series 2
  - School Ephemera (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pre-School Writings and Drawings (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Course descriptions and grades: Primary School (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - School Papers: Arithmetic, Geography (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 8/31/1914 (Sear’s 6th birthday) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: classmates to Robert re. his surgery ca. 1918 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Personal notes re. getting up for school (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - High School and Stanford ephemera (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Drama Papers: Palo Alto Union High School (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Palo Alto Union High School: Diploma (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Palo Alto Union High School Commencement: programs and newsclippings; High School Stage Productions, programs. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - “The A-S Reaction Study” completed by Robert Sears (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - English Theme, 1923. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - School Papers: Palo Alto High School (includes Short Stories), 1923-1925 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - “Madrona”: Palo Alto Union High School yearbook: 1923-1925 (Box 4)
  - Short Stories and papers (High School or Stanford) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Short Stories and papers (High School or Stanford) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Short Stories and papers (High School or Stanford) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Short Stories and papers: Stanford (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - School Notes: Stanford (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - “The Stanford Lit.” and “The Stanford Literary Magazine,” 1926 & 1928. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stanford “Datebook” and 1925-1926 Handbook (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Syllabus: “Medieval Europe,” 1926 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Syllabus, “Problems of Citizenship,” 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Syllabus, “Herodotus,” 1925 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Syllabus, “Greek History,” 1926 and personal notes (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Syllabus, “Russian Art,” 1926 and “Slavic Literature,” 1925 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Syllabi, 1925-1926 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “Homeric Troy” (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chemistry 4 School Lab book, 1925: Stanford (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - “Essays and Notes on English Literature form Beowulf to Shakespeare,” ca. 1929 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Sears’ Play Reviews and “Intellectual Diary” (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Theater Programs (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - “Out of India” by Robert Sears, as published in The Campanile (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Items: Newsclippings, Theater Programs, Poems, Notes (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - English 184, History 24: 1928 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Post Stanford: “Hypnotic Anesthesia” (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Sears Family: Correspondence, Series 3
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), 1905 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), 1906-1907 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), 1908 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Incoming corr. re. Robert’s birth and early childhood, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), Jan.-Sept. 24, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), Sept. 26 - Dec., 1909 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), 1910 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), Jan. - July 1911 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), Aug. - Dec. 1911 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (incoming), 1912-1913 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Robert’s “grandmother,” 1913 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1922-1929 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1930 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan. - June 1931 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Nov. - Dec., 1931 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1932 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), May-July, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Aug.-Oct., 1934 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Nov.-Dec., 1934 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1935 (re. wedding) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1935 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1935 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-Sept., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Oct.-Dec., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-March, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), April-July, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Sept.-Dec., 1937 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-Aug., 1938 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Sept.-Dec., 1938 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Sept. - Dec., 1939 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan. - May, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), June-Dec., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1941 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1942 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1943 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-July, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Aug.-Dec., 1944 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-May, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), June-Dec., 1945 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-March, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), April-June, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), July-Nov., 1946 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Dec., 1946 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-April, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), May-Sept., 1947 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Oct. - Dec., 1947 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Jan.-April, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), May-Sept., 1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), Oct.-Dec., 1948 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), 1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jesse & Stella Sears (outgoing), undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), 1918 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), 1925 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), 1926-1928 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), 1929 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), Jan.-May, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), June-Dec., 1930 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), Jan.-July, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), Aug.-Dec., 1931 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1932 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1933 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-April, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), May-June, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July-Dec, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-July, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Aug.-Dec, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1936 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July-Dec., 1937 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1938 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July-Dec., 1940 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1941 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1942 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1943 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Aug.-Dec., 1944 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Aug.-Dec., 1945 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-April, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), May-Oct., 1946 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Nov.-Dec., 1946 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July-Dec., 1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), July-Dec., 1948 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1949 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Robert, Pauline, and David Sears (outgoing), 1950 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1951 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1952 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Robert, Pauline, and David Sears (outgoing), 1953 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1957 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), ND (ca. 1944-1950) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), ND (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Robert Sears (outgoing), misc. ND (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Robert Sears to Kenneth Pitzer, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (outgoing), 1972 (includes family members) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1930-1935 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1935-1936 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1937 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1938 (with photographs) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1939 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1940 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1940 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1944 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1945 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1946 (with photographs) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., Lewis Terman, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Robert Sears: Incoming corr., 1969- (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Pauline Sears: Incoming corr., 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sears: Incoming corr., ND (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Norman Sears, 1930-1971 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Edith Sears (Tysie), 1943-1972 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Snedden Family: Correspondence, Series 4
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1932 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1934 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), July-Dec., 1935 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-Feb., 1936 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), March-April 3, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), April 11-May, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Sept.-Dec., 1936 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-April, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), May-August, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Sept.-Dec., 1938 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-April, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), May-Dec., 1939 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan-April, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), May-Dec., 1940 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1941 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1943 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-May, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), June-Dec., 1944 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), July-Dec., 1945 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-June, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), July-Dec., 1946 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Jan.-July, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), Aug.-Dec., 1947 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1948 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), 1949, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), ND (ca. 1936-1940) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - David and Genevra Snedden (outgoing), ND (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1909 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1936 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1937-1938 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1939-1940 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1942-1944 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Hope Snedden and Leonard Carlsmith, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Hope Snedden and Leonard Carlsmith, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), 1948 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Hope Snedden (outgoing), ND (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Janet Snedden (outgoing), 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Janet Snedden (outgoing), 1938 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Janet Snedden (outgoing), 1939-1941 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Janet Snedden (outgoing), 1943-1948 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Ruth Snedden (outgoing), 1935-1948 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Sears Family: Journals/Business Papers, Series 5
  - Sears: Retirement Arrangements (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Sears: House papers, 22 Appian Way House (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Sears: House papers, 181 Coleridge, Palo Alto (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Sears: House related (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Sears: Business/Legal (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Sears: Art Gallery receipts (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Sears/Stanford University Archives Agreement (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Financial Journal, 1921-1936 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Financial Journal, 1937-1971 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Financial Journal, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Checking Acct. Journal, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Financial Journals (3) (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Sears Family: Miscellaneous, Series 6
  - Harry Johnson Sears Autobiography (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Pauline Sears, VITA (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Norman Sears, Christmas gift, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Sears: clippings and articles (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Sears: clippings and articles (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Robert Sears: Press release (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Pauline and Robert Sears: retirement papers (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Notes found in Identification and Child Rearing by Robert Sears (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - “Papers Published in Journals, Bulletins, Yearbooks, and Proceedings, 1915-1953,” by Jesse B. Sears (Box 20)
- Sears/Snedden: Photographs, Series 7
  - Sears Family (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - J.B. Sears (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - J.B. Sears (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Robert Sears (early school) (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Robert Sears (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Robert Sears (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Robert and Pauline Sears (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Sears (houses, pets, etc.) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Snedden Family (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - unknown (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Misc. negatives (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Glass slide: High School Play Production (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Snedden Family, 1 film reel(s) (8mm) (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - unknown, 1 film reel(s) (8mm) (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Sears/Snedden: Ephemera, Publications, Oversize, Series 8
  - Sears: WW II ephemera (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Sears: WW II ephemera (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Sears: WW II ephemera (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Sears: WW II ephemera (photographs: NDRC gunnery) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Sears: WW II ephemera (16 mm film: NDRC gunnery, 2 rolls) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Snedden Family publications
    - 1. “Anna O’Keefe and Samuel Snedden, 1867-1975” (compiled by Virginia Culbert, 1975) (Box 23)
    - 2. “Six Generations in California: Anna O’Keefe & Samuel Snedden 1867-1986” (compiled by Virginia Culbert, 1985) (Box 23)
    - 3. “Mountain Cattle and Frontier People” - Genevra Sisson Snedden (Box 23)
    - 4. “Docas, Indian of Santa Clara” - Genevra S. Snedden (Box 23)
    - 5. “A Memorial to Genevra Sisson Snedden” - David Snedden (2 cc) (Box 23)
    - 6. “Recollections” - David Snedden (2 cc) (Box 23)
  - Robert Sears: ephemera (includes books, artwork as child) (Box 24)
  - Robert Sears: ephemera (newspaper clippings, awards, photographs, drawings) (Box 25)
  - File box: Psychology Test questions/answers (on file cards) (Box 26)
- Additional Materials, Accession ARCH_2018_001
  - Harvard School of Education - Lab of Human Development., 1952 Jun (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harvard - David and Nancy (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Harvard - Robert R. Sears; Pauline Snedden Sears (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harvard - Robert R. Sears; Pauline Snedden Sears (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stanford, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pauline Snedden Sears - Reprints (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pauline Snedden Sears - Reprints (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CASBS, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Boys Town proposal, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SRCD Gov. Council. Annual report, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Robert R. Sears - Speeches (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Robert R. Sears - Montreal Congress, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Harvard (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Illinois: Robert R. Sears and Pauline Snedden Sears, 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Illinois: Robert R. Sears and Pauline Snedden Sears: photos, 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Illinois. Faculty and student directory, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Yale: Robert R. Sears and Pauline Snedden Sears, 1936-1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Iowa: Robert R. Sears and Pauline Snedden Sears, 1942-1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)